(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
ビターチョコデコレーション
作詞・作曲：syudou
Bitter Chocolate Decoration
Lyrics & Composition: syudou
人に過度に信じないように
I try not to have too much faith in people,
愛さないように
not to love them too much,
期待しないように
and not to expect too much.
かと言って角が立たないように
On the other hand, I try not to cause offense,
気取らぬように
not to act all high and mighty,
目立たぬように
and not to stand out.
誰一人傷つけぬように
I try not to hurt anyone,
いじめぬように
not to pick on anyone,
殺さぬように
and not to kill anyone.
かと言って偽善がばれないように
On the other hand, I try not to let my hypocrisy show,
威張らぬように
and not to get on my high horse.
軽いジョークやリップサービスも忘れないように
I try not to forget light jokes and lip service,
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
and to always smile and act charming.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration,
とにかく言わずに酸惨と召し上がれ
anyway, eat it up bitterly without saying a word.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration,
食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなくちゃ
you really need to fix your pickiness.
頭空っぽその後に
Once your head is completely empty,
残る心が本物なら
if the heart left behind is the real thing,
きっと君と同じこと
surely you'll do the exact same thing.
そこにあるだけ
It's just there.
やっぱいいや
Ah, never mind.
無駄に自我を晒さぬように
Don't expose your ego in vain.
話さぬように 分からぬように
Don't speak, don't understand.
でも絶対口を閉ざさぬように
But definitely don't keep your mouth shut either.
笑わすより笑われるように
Rather than making people laugh, try to be the one laughed at.
人をちゃんと敬うように
Try to respect people properly.
崇めるように 讃えるように
Try to worship them, praise them.
でも決して嫌味にならないように
But never let it sound sarcastic.
ふざけないように
Don't mess around.
集団参加の終身刑
It's a life sentence of group participation.
またへーこらへーこら言っちゃって
And you say "yes sir, yes sir" again.
「あれっ、前髪ちょーぜつさいきょーじゃん!」
"Oh, your bangs look super great!"
とかどーでもいーのに言っちゃって
Even though it doesn't matter, you say things like that.
毎朝毎晩もう限界
Every morning, every night, I've reached my limit.
宗教的社会の集団リンチ
It's a group lynching in a religious society.
でも決して発狂しないように
But never let yourself snap.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration
時に孤独な愛は君を汚す
Sometimes lonely love stains you.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration
立つ鳥の後きっと糞のアート
The art of excrement left behind by a bird.
初めはあんな大層な大言壮語を並べたが
At first I lined up such grand, big-talking words,
嫌よ嫌よも好きの内
but "no" means "yes".
「いやはやしかし今日が初めてで
"Oh, well, today is the first time,
こんなとはね 君センスあるよ」
I didn't expect this, you have good sense."
恋する季節にビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration in the season of love
恋する気持ちでビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration with feelings of love
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration
皆が望む理想に憧れて
Longing for the ideal that everyone desires,
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration
固定観念は全部焼き払い
burning away all fixed ideas.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration
欲やエゴは殺して土に埋め
Kill off greed and ego and bury them in the dirt.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter chocolate decoration
僕は大人にやっと成ったよママ保存
I've finally become an adult, Mama.
明日もきっとこの先も保存
Tomorrow as well, and from here on out,
地獄は続く何処までも
the hell will continue endlessly.
だからどうか今だけは
So please, at least for now,
子供の心のままで保存
keep your childhood heart,
意志を伴わずにやってこうぜ
and let's do this without carrying any will.
あぁ、思い出して
Ah, remember...
やっぱいいや
Ah, never mind.
サイコロ...
A die...
よいしょ...保存
Heave-ho...
重い...
It's heavy...
えい！
Here goes!
５が出た！
It rolled a 5!
え？何これ？
Huh? What is this?
えい...
Step...
椅子？
A chair?
One, two, one
アップダウンは世の常
Ups and downs are the way of the world.
クズ引いたって動じない
Even if you're a loser, don't panic.
肝心なの Strong な Mind
What's essential is a strong mind.
出し抜いて Survive
Get ahead and survive.
行きつく先は Heaven or hell
The place you end up is heaven or hell.
この世界のルール たった一つ
The rules of this world, there is only one:
勝者こそが正義
the winner is justice.
女は度胸
Women have guts.
焦れさせるのアイツを
I'll make him anxious.
やれること なんだってやる
I'll do whatever it takes.
あたしは賭け狂いのクイーン
I'm the gambling queen.
お見通しそれ You doubt me
I see through you, you doubt me.
読み切って
Read it all,
レッツ Showdown!
let's showdown!
Deal with the devil保存
Deal with the devil
見透かして あなたの髪の一本まで全部
See through it, down to every single hair on your head.
A million dollars I'd say raise保存
A million dollars I'd say raise.
震えてるわよ 坊や
You're trembling, boy.
降ろさせはしないわ
I won't let you fold.
Deal with the devil保存
Deal with the devil
あぁ、興奮！
Ah, excitement!
誰にも触らせない この Money
I won't let anyone touch this money.
A million dollars I'd say raise保存
A million dollars I'd say raise.
さあ Com'on 覚悟キメて
Come on, make up your mind.
震え高ぶれ My heart
Tremble, rise up, my heart.
欲しがるようじゃね まだベイビー
If you want it, you're still a baby.
誰にも負けない
I won't lose to anyone.
感じさせて
Make me feel it,
あなた内緒だわ
It's a secret for you.
ほら見せてあげる
Look, I'll show you.
秘密って甘いの
Secrets are sweet.
仕掛けて罠に嵌めるわ...
I'll set a trap and catch you...
油断誘うのよ
I'll tempt you, I'll make you bend.
思考を止めたらジ・エンド
Take time to second guess and it's the end.
何にも知らないような表情で...
I'll play innocent as...
堕とすわあなたを
I bring your world crumbling down.
虚勢でしょそれ you doubt me
That's just a bluff, you doubt me?
読み切ってレッツ showdown
Thought you had me? Let's showdown!
Deal with the devil 見逃さない
Deal with the devil, you won't get past me!
どんな小さなズルだって
No matter how miniscule the cheat...
あたしの目はごまかされないわ
There's nothing these eyes of mine can't see!
a million dollars i'd say raise
勝った相手は骨まで
I want to conquer you completely...
愛しつくしてあげる
Then I'll love you and you'll never leave me!
狙った獲物は逃がさない
You're my prey and there's no way you'll leave my sight.
唇濡らして頂くわ my babe
Wet my lips and call it fate, my babe.
ダイヤのジャックで手が揃うわ
The Jack of Diamonds! This has been worth it.
笑みを殺し待つだけ
I hide my smile and patiently wait.
あたしのポーカーフェイスは it's perfect
Can't see through my poker face, why, it's perfect!
一分の隙も見せたりしないわ
It never falters, you're only wasting your time.
視線感じてるわ...
I feel your gaze on my skin...
お望みは最後まで
All the desires that you're holding in.
見てばっかりいないで
Why try to save them?
あたしとしていかない？
It would be so much fun if you'd play with me.
負けるのが怖い？ you're easy game
So, what, you're scared to lose? You're easy game!
読み切ってレッツ showdown
Thought you had me? Let's showdown!
Deal with the devil 見透かして
Deal with the devil, I see your lies.
あたしのものにする
No matter the cost, I'll make you mine.
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
Down to every hair, I will own you.
a million dollars i'd say raise
震えてるわよ坊や
I can't stop trembling with excitement!
とことんまで行くわ
C'mon boy, let's go until I'm spent!
Deal with the devil, uhn 興奮
Deal with the devil, oh, I want more!
たまらないわスリル
The endlessly thrilling time in store.
誰にも触らせないこの money
I won't let you touch it, all this money!
a million dollars i'd say raise
さあ com'on 覚悟キメて
So come on, hurry, make your mind up!
ハイになるまで打って
Until we hit high, don't you dare stop!
欲しがるようじゃねまだベイビー
Only ever making wishes, you naive baby.
誰にも負けない
No one else can make me feel it.
感じさせて love me honey
Come give it all to me, love me, honey~
ふう... はあ... ほら、椅子も無くなっちゃった。
Phew... Oh, the chairs are gone too.
もうちょっと座らせてほしかった。
I wanted to sit a little longer.
はーいみんな！見えてる？聞こえてる？
Hello everyone! Can you see me? Can you hear me?
ホロライブ所属の癒し系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
I'm the healing half-elf from Hololive, Aki Rosenthal, also known as Akirose!
ハロー、ハロー、アローナ！
Hello, hello, Alona!
えー、今回の「アキロゼ生誕祭2026」へようこそ！
Welcome to the Akirose Birthday Festival 2026!
ふう... はあ... 早速ね、なんか色々行われていたんですが...
Phew... right off the bat, there's a lot going on...
一体今回のライブはどうなっちゃうのか...
...but how is this concert going to turn out?
ぜひ最後まで必見、お見逃しなくお願いします！
Please stay tuned until the very end, don't miss it!
今回のライブのハッシュタグは「#アキロゼ生誕祭2026」、
The hashtag for today's live is "#アキロゼ生誕祭2026".
こちらをつけてXにたくさんポストしてね！
Please post a lot on X with this hashtag!
もちろん「かわいい」「美しい」のスクショ、アハァン。
Of course, post your "cute" and "beautiful" screenshots, ah-ha~!
えー、もたくさん撮って、合わせてポストしてください。
Please take lots of screenshots and post them too!
ライブが終わった後、アキロゼ見に行きます！見てね。
After the concert, Akirose will check them! Look forward to it.
あ、チャンネル登録もよろしくね！
Oh, and please subscribe to my channel too!
オッケー？撮って撮って、はいありがとう！
Okay? Take lots of pictures. Yes, thank you!
ほお？お？なんだ？
Oh? What is this?
なに、なに、なに？え？
What, what, what? Huh?
んー、ていうかここどこなんだろう。
Wait, where am I anyway?
お！あんなところにルーレットがある！
Oh! There's a roulette wheel over there!
え？回るのかな？
Huh? Does it spin?
お、え、ま、回った！え、すごい！
Oh, wait, it's spinning! Wow, that's amazing!
もう回った！
It's already spinning!
えー、何が出るんだろう？
Uh, what will it be?
お、え、お、え？ な、何何？
O-Oh, wh-what is it?
どうなっちゃうの？
What is going to happen?
ピース？
Peace?
お？ ん？何だ？
Oh? Hmm? What is that?
unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? O, child of man in torment...
unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even those who are not human...
be happy! 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep aiming for it unceasingly!
アンデッド！生きているんだし
Undead! Since we are alive after all!
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past we turned away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future...
カウンセリング
Counseling,
やれやれ...
oh dear.
古今東西ピースピース
All over the world, peace peace!
ねえねえねえねえ 何とかどうしても
Hey, hey, hey, hey, somehow, no matter what,
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting...
逃げられない 触れたくもない
Can't escape, don't even want to touch...
過去の自分
my past self.
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost that's long been dead...
痛い痛い痛い記憶の奥
deep within painful, painful, painful memories.
残念？もう居ないのに
What a shame? Even though I'm no longer here...
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Oh? Is that better? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self that is being seen through?
ナンセンス
Nonsense!
消えないレッテル
An indelible label...
いえ、要はコンプレックス
No, in short, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま まだ離れない
Still wound around, still not letting go...
在りし日の自分
my self from the past.
アンデッド！
Undead!
信じられない お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and yourself unable to trust each other...
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing!
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't settle for and be satisfied with unhappiness!
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly to not even try to be happy!
この世 この世は 奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will it be a demon or a snake that comes out next?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
A story that finally begins when we meet and encounter.
さあ人か化物か 閑話休題
Now, is it a human or a monster? But I digress...
ピースピース
Peace, peace!
Ah, the future can't change the past.
Past and future, love for the future.
ねえねえねえねえ 何だかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, hey, somehow, why...
未来に何となくそんな気がするの
is it that I feel somehow like that about the future?
守れない 守りたくもない
Can't protect, don't even want to protect...
余計なお世話をして
minding other people's business.
もう随分生きてる 意趣返しテンプレートを消去
Having lived for so long, erasing the template of retaliation...
不敵に笑う出来事の気配すら無い
there is not even a sign of events that make you smile fearlessly.
残念？積んだ経験
What a shame? The experience you've gained...
案外、形骸化された自分は退屈の進化？
Surprisingly, is my hollowed-out self an evolution of boredom?
要は刺激が欲しいの 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
In short, I want stimulation; I got tired of it, got used to it.
ナンセンス
Nonsense!
固まってくバイアス
A hardening bias...
say!歪なコンプライアンス
Say! A distorted compliance...
すりつぶされていくみたい
It's like I'm being ground down.
澄み渡りすぎて
It's too clear...
あれもこれそれも同じ味がする
this, that, and everything else tastes the same.
アンデッド！
Undead!
信じられない お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and yourself unable to trust each other...
いつの世も過去も未来も今に在るんだ
In any age, the past and the future both exist in the now!
生きていることを無気力に果たすなよ保存
Don't live your life listlessly!
One!
見つめる作戦
The staring strategy!
Two!
見つめ合えば
If our eyes meet...
Three!
おー
Oh...
止められない！
I can't stop!
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah Yeah Yeah, with this love, with this affection
Melting Melting とろけちゃうよ
Melting, melting, I'm going to melt!
ねえ ねえ ねえ 気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
届けて 大好き
Deliver it, I love you!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
かるびちゃん！
Karubi-chan!
はーい！
Present!
何が好き？
What do you like?
チョコミント！よりも、あ・な・た！
Chocomint! No, actually, Y-O-U!
おるちゃん！
Ollie-chan!
はーい！
Present!
何が好き？
What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりも、あ・な・た！
Strawberry flavor! No, actually, Y-O-U!
アキちゃん！
Aki-chan!
はーい！
Present!
何が、好き？
What do you like?
クッキー＆クリーム！よりも、あ・な・た！
Cookie & Cream! No, actually, Y-O-U!
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Present!
何が、好き？
What do you like?
もちろん 大好き アイスクリーム！
Of course, we love ice cream!
止められない！
I can't stop!
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah Yeah Yeah, with this love, with this affection
Melting Melting とろけちゃうよ
Melting, melting, I'm going to melt!
ねえ ねえ ねえ 気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
ちょー 大好き
I super love you!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
お願い 見つけて My darling
Please find me, my darling!
お願い 気づいて My darling
Please notice me, my darling!
One!
勇気を出して
Plucking up some courage!
Two!
近づく作戦
The getting closer strategy!
Three!
手と手が触れて
If our hands touch...
Four!
おー
Oh...
止められない！
I can't stop!
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah Yeah Yeah, with this love, with this affection
Melting Melting とろけちゃうよ
Melting, melting, I'm going to melt!
ねえ ねえ ねえ 気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
それなら あなた
In that case, you!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイスクリーム アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 食べましょう
Ice cream, ice cream, let's eat ice cream!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
La La La...
あ、元気もらうって、面白くって、オレンジで...
Ah, energetic, funny, and Orange...
シャンパンコール得意な人いないかな〜？
Is there anyone good at champagne calls?
それ、俺らじゃないかーい！
Isn't that us?!
Na Na Na...
チョットでいいから みせてくれないか
Just a little is fine, won't you show me?
お前のセクシー フェロモンで おれ メロメロ
With your sexy pheromones, I'm melting
AH ふれちゃいそう でも イケナイの！
Ah, it seems like I might touch it, but it's forbidden!
徐々に高鳴る鼓動 とめられないわ
The heartbeat that gradually rises cannot be stopped
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
The memory of the words exchanged is far away
口元の動きに揺られ動く
shaken and moved by the movement of the lips...
の動きに揺れ動く
...swaying in the movement of your lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah Ah
I stroke your wet hair and then, ah, ah.
ABC続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, it's no good like that.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない？
But isn't it different deep in your heart?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't like that, I want to finish hot inside.
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
It must be you or I don't want it.
オレはイケナイ太陽
I'm the forbidden sun.
Na Na Na...
あぁ 赤い糸なんて絵空事
Ah, the red thread is a pipe dream.
でも下心でさえ信じたいの
But I want to believe even in my motives.
俺は正しい キミも正しい
I'm right, you're right too.
とにかくもう左右されないゼ
Anyway, I won't be swayed anymore.
騙し騙され胸うずく
Deceiving and being deceived, my heart aches.
下手な芝居がより盛り上げる夜
A terrible drama brings the night to a climax.
息が耳に触れた二人 Ah
Our breaths meet each other's ears, ah.
ABC続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, it's no good like that.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない？
But isn't it different deep in your heart?
あたしの青春 そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't like that, I want to finish hot inside.
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
It must be you or I don't want it.
あたしイケナイ太陽
I'm the forbidden sun.
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
Memories of the words we exchanged are far away.
口元の動きに揺れ動く
Swaying in the movement of your lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた
I stroke your wet hair.
そして Ah Ah
And then, ah, ah.
ABC続かない そんなんじゃ ダメじゃない
ABC won't continue, it's no good like that.
だって ココロの奥は違うんじゃない？
But isn't it different deep in your heart?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't like that,
早い早い！
So fast, so fast!
お忙しい人気者だ！
You're a busy, popular person!
お忙しいな！
You're so busy!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
賑やかで楽しかった！
Ah, it was so lively and fun!
ふふん
Hmm...
まるでこの世界で
It's almost as if in this world...
二人だけみたいだね
...we're the only two people.
なんて
Is what I thought...
すこしだけ
...just for a little bit,
夢を見てしまっただけ
just a dream I ended up having.
つま先に月明かり
Moonlight at my toes,
花束の香り
the scent of a bouquet,
指にふれる指
finger touching finger.
さよなら　もう行かなきゃ
Goodbye, I have to go now,
なにもかも忘れて
forgetting absolutely everything.
ガラスの上を裸足のまま歩く
Walking on glass with bare feet,
傷むごとに血が流れて落ちていく
with every pain, blood flows and drops.
お願い　その赤い足跡を
Please, follow those red footprints...
たどって会いに来て
...and come to see me.
錆びたプールに放たれていく金魚
Goldfish released into a rusted pool,
薬箱の中隠したリンゴ
an apple hidden inside a medicine box.
萎びた君の肌にぬかる傷跡
The muddy scars on your withered skin,
犬のように泳いだ迷子
like a lost child swimming like a dog.
どこにいるの
Where are you?
何をしてるの
What are you doing?
この世を間違いで満たそう
Let's fill this world with mistakes.
そばにいたよ
I was by your side.
遊びに行こう
Let's go play.
どこにいるの
Where are you?
ガラスの上を裸足のまま歩く
Walking on glass with bare feet,
傷むごとに血が流れて落ちていく
with every pain, blood flows and drops.
お願い　その赤い足跡を
Please, follow those red footprints...
たどって会いに来て
...and come to see me.
愛に来て
Come to love me.
まるでこの世界で
It's almost as if in this world...
二人だけ...
...we're the only two...
なんて
Is what I thought...
すこしだけ
...just for a little bit,
夢を見てしまっただけ
just a dream I ended up having.
さあ、選択の時だ
Now, it's time to choose.
コイン
Coin.
このコインは...
This coin is...
はぁ... そうか。君はそっちなんだね。
Ah... I see. So you're on that side.
そっち？
That side?
ここに座って。
Sit here.
えっ...
Eh...?
この後は君次第だよ。
What happens next is up to you.
忘れられないのはこの目のせい
It's these eyes' fault that I can't forget
赤く残る過ち甘噛みの跡
About the red stains of my errors or the traces of play-biting
溢れだす愛は止めどもない
The overflowing love doesn't even have an end
誰もいない間に悪魔を探す
While there's no one else around, I search for the devil
作り笑いはこの耳のせい
It's these ears' fault that my smiles are strained
深い壁の中から呼びかける声
From within the thick walls, a voice calls out to me
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ触らせない
whisper, whisper, whisper, but it still doesn't let me touch
この檻を抜け出して悪魔は駆ける
The devil breaks out of this cage and races away
鏡の前でこの口のせい
It's this mouth's fault that I'm in front of the mirror,
伝えたい言葉さえ噛み殺す夜
stifling even the words I want to say tonight
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ打ち明けない
whisper, whisper, whisper, but I still won't open my heart
神様を裏切って悪魔と過ごす
I turn my back on God and while away time with the devil
曖昧に
Vaguely
夢見ていたい あなたに
I want to dream... to you,
そっと気付かせてあげたいだけ
I want to gently make you realize, that's all
oh あなたにも
Oh, even you
消えない
Unfading
傷を隠したい あなたに
I want to hide my scars... to you,
そっと悩ませてあげたいだけ
I want to gently make you worry, that's all
oh あなたにも
Oh, even you
悪魔を探す
I search for the devil
作り笑いはこの耳のせい
It's these ears' fault that my smiles are strained
深い壁の中から呼びかける声
From within the thick walls, a voice calls out to me
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ触らせない
whisper, whisper, whisper, but it still doesn't let me touch
この檻を抜け出して悪魔は駆ける
The devil breaks out of this cage and races away
鏡の前でこの口のせい
It's this mouth's fault that I'm in front of the mirror,
伝えたい言葉さえ噛み殺す夜
stifling even the words I want to say tonight
whisper, whisper, whisper まだ打ち明けない
whisper, whisper, whisper, but I still won't open my heart
神様を裏切って悪魔と過ごす
I turn my back on God and while away time with the devil
好き嫌い常識 I don't care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Suki, kirai, common sense, I don't care! Blow it away, BANG!!!
かかってこい majority あたしに負けはなし
Come at me, majority! I never lose
ここまでって引かれたそのボーダー 誰のルール？
That border drawn up to here, whose rule is it?
あの日乗り越えた weak heart
Overcoming that weak heart from that day,
強くなったあたしが笑い飛ばしてあげる
a stronger me will laugh it all off
言いたい事は言う
I'm gonna say what I want to say
やりたくない事はしない
I won't do what I don't want to do
悪意気にしない
I don't care about malice
皆違うの当然だし あたしも変わんない
It's natural for everyone to be different, and I won't change
ニューノーマルの時代
This is the era of the new normal
(Everybody say I want to be free)
YesもNoも言わない それじゃ何も変えられない
Not saying yes or no won't change anything
(Everybody say I want to live more)
叶えたい自分肯定 生きてるんだあたし
Fulfilling my self-affirmation, I am alive!
ねえ 生きてるんだあたし
Hey, I am alive!
歌えや歌え今を (声あげて)
Sing, sing, for the present! (Raise your voice!)
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've been choosing since the moment I was born
思い出せ あたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am myself!
不可能なことなど何一つもない 嘘じゃない
Nothing is impossible, it's not a lie
なりたい自分に
Into the self I want to be
好き嫌い常識 I don't care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Suki, kirai, common sense, I don't care! Blow it away, BANG!!!
(Again)
好き嫌い常識 I don't care 吹っ飛べ BANG!!!
Suki, kirai, common sense, I don't care! Blow it away, BANG!!!
フルテン鳴らす
Sounding it out at full volume,
このリリックかます
blasting this lyric,
わからす挑発
provoking to make you understand,
下向いて舌打ちからの "は？"
looking down, clicking my tongue, then "Huh?"
(Excuse me)
あしからず倍返し
No hard feelings, but I'll pay you back double
食らえパンチライン
Take this punchline!
聴かせてあげる
I'll let you hear it
やってやるから考えな
I'll show you what I've got, so watch out
アタシがついてるから
Because I've got your back
Everybody say I want to be free
喰らうこのビート 空間全部黙らす
Take in this beat, it silences the entire space
Shout it out! Shout it out!
目覚ませ 鳴らせ BANG!!! 突き破る私
Wake up, make it ring, BANG!!! Breaking through is me
BANG!!! 突き破る私
BANG!!! I'll break right through!
ねぇ、BANG!!! 突き破る私
Hey, BANG!!! I'll break right through!
BANG!!! 突き破る私
BANG!!! I'll break right through!
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
I've chosen my path since the day I was born
思い出せ 私は私だ
Remember, I am myself
不可能なことなど何一つもない
There is absolutely nothing that is impossible
信じなさい
Believe in yourself
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ
You've chosen your path since the day you were born
思い出せ あなたはあなただ
Remember, you are yourself
不可能なことなど何一つもない
There is absolutely nothing that is impossible
信じなさい 自分に
Believe in yourself
Hate, Like, Trust, Doubt, I don't care, 吹っ飛べ BANG!
Hate, like, trust, doubt, I don't care, blow them away, BANG!
Bad Apple!!
作詞: Haruka / 作曲: ZUN
[Song: Bad Apple!!]
[Lyrics: Haruka / Composition: ZUN]
流れてく時の中ででも
Even in the midst of flowing time,
気だるさがほらグルグル廻って
I feel languid, look, spinning around and around,
私から離れる心も
and even the heart that's leaving me
見えないわそう知らない？
I cannot see, didn't you know?
自分から動くこともなく
Without even getting myself to move,
時の隙間に流され続けて
I continue to drift through the cracks of time.
知らないわ周りのことなど
I don't know anything about my surroundings,
私は私それだけ
I am just myself, and no more.
夢見てる？なにも見てない？
Am I dreaming? Or seeing nothing?
語るも無駄な自分の言葉
My own words are useless to even speak.
悲しむなんて疲れるだけよ
Being sad will only wear me out,
何も感じず過ごせばいいの
so it's fine to just live without feeling anything.
戸惑う言葉与えられても
Even if I'm given words of confusion,
自分の心ただ上の空
my heart is just somewhere else.
もし私から動くのならば
If I were to move of my own accord,
すべて変えるのなら黒にする
and if I were to change everything, I'd make it black.
こんな自分に未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に私はいるの？
Do I even exist in a world like this?
今切ないの？今悲しいの？
Am I in pain now? Am I sad now?
自分の事もわからないまま
Without even understanding myself,
歩むことさえ疲れるだけよ
even walking will only wear me out.
人のことなど知りもしないわ
I don't know or care about anyone else.
こんな私も変われるのなら
If even someone like me can change,
もし変われるのなら白になる
if I can change, I will turn white.
流れてく時の中ででも
Even in the midst of flowing time,
気だるさがほらグルグル廻って
I feel languid, look, spinning around and around,
私から離れる心も
and even the heart that's leaving me
見えないわそう知らない？
I cannot see, didn't you know?
自分から動くこともなく
Without even getting myself to move,
時の隙間に流され続けて
I continue to drift through the cracks of time.
知らないわ周りのことなど
I don't know anything about my surroundings,
私は私それだけ
I am just myself, and no more.
夢見てる？なにも見てない？
Am I dreaming? Or seeing nothing?
語るも無駄な自分の言葉
My own words are useless to even speak.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Being sad only tires me out...
何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
I should just get by without feeling a thing.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if I'm given words of confusion,
自分の心 ただ上の空
My heart is just somewhere else.
もし私から 動くのならば
If I were to move of my own accord,
すべて変えるのなら 黒にする
If I'm to change everything, I'll turn it black.
動くのならば 動くのならば
If I am to move, if I am to move,
すべて壊すわ すべて壊すわ
I will destroy everything, I will destroy everything.
哀しむならば 哀しむならば
If I am to grieve, if I am to grieve,
私の心 白く変われる？
Can my heart turn white?
あなたのことも 私のことも
About you, about me,
すべてのことも まだ知らないの
And about everything else, I still don't know.
重い瞼を 開けたのならば
If I were to open my heavy eyelids...
すべて壊すのなら 黒になれ
If I'm to destroy everything, let it turn black!
Magia / 作詞・作曲：梶浦由記
Magia / Lyrics & Composition: Yuki Kajiura
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
The light of love that you will one day ignite in your eyes
時を超えて
Will cross through time,
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を
And surely, it will destroy one dream
確かに一つ壊すだろう
Of a world that is rushing toward destruction.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallowing up your hesitation,
君が望むモノは何？
What is the thing that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
In the outcome of such greedy longing,
儚い明日はあるの？
Is there a fleeting tomorrow?
子供の頃夢に見てた
Just like the ancient magic
古の魔法のように
I dreamed of when I was a child,
闇さえ砕く力で
With the power to crush even the darkness,
微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you, smiling.
怯えるこの手の中には
Inside these trembling hands of mine
手折られた花の勇気
Is the courage of a flower that has been snapped off.
想いだけが頼る全て流通
My feelings are all I have to rely on,
光を呼び覚ます
They are the wish that awakens the light:
願い
A prayer.
いつか君も誰かの為に購入
One day, you too will desire great power
強い力を望むのだろう
For the sake of someone else.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に
On the night that love captures your heart,
未知の言葉が生まれて来る
Unknown words will be born.
迷わずに行けるなら
If I can go without hesitation,
心が砕けてもいいわ
I don't care if my heart breaks.
いつも目の前の哀しみに
I want a spell to face
立ち向かう為の呪文が欲しい
The sadness always in front of me.
君はまだ夢見る記憶
You are still a memory that dreams,
私は眠らない明日
And I am a tomorrow that does not sleep.
二人が出会う奇跡を
I will move forward to win
勝ち取る為に進むわ
The miracle of us two meeting.
怯えるこの手の中には
Inside these trembling hands of mine
手折られた花の刃
Is the blade of a flower that has been snapped off.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings are all I have to live by,
心に振りかざす
They are the wish I wield against my heart:
願い
A prayer.
囚われた太陽の輝く
The shining of the captured sun...
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
Back when I loved books about Wonderland...
願いはきっと叶うと
Believing that wishes will surely come true...
教えるお伽噺を信じた
I believed in those fairy tales.
光と影の中
(In the midst of light and shadow)
静かに咲き乱れていた 古の魔法優しく
The ancient magic gently ran wild in quiet bloom,
世界を変える力が その手にあると囁く
whispering that the power to change the world is in your hands.
終わらない夢を見よう 君と行く時の中で
Let's dream an endless dream in the time I walk with you.
想いだけが生きる全て
My thoughts are all that live on...
命を作るのは 願い
What creates life is a wish.
うわー！わー！イェーイ！
Wow! Yay!
アキちゃん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Aki-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！イェーイ！ありがとう！
Thank you! Yay! Thank you!
今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
こちらこそですよ、ありがとうございます！呼んでくれてありがとう！
Likewise, thank you! Thank you for inviting us!
実はね、二人を呼んだのにはちょっと理由があって...
Actually, there's a reason why I invited you two...
お？なんだなんだ？
Oh? What is it, what is it?
前に、アキロゼの4周年のときに、3人でカラフィナさんの曲を歌わせてもらったんだけど
Before, for my 4th anniversary, the three of us got to sing a Kalafina song together.
やりましたね！めっちゃ良かったよね！そうそう！ハモりがね！
We did! It was so good! Yes, the harmonies!
そう！もうね、ミオちゃんの歌も大好きだし、フブちゃんの歌も大好きだし、あのね、忘れられないの！
Yes! I love Mio-chan's singing, and I love Fubu-chan's singing too. I just can't forget it!
わかる！めっちゃ良かった！
I know! It was so good!
だからもう一回、このライブステージで3人で歌いたくて、今日は来てもらいました！
So I wanted to sing together on this live stage again, which is why I asked you to come today!
嬉しい！ありがとう！ありがとう！
We're so happy! Thank you so much!
だから、これを機に、もっと3人で歌ったりとか、そういうの挑戦できたらめっちゃ嬉しい！
So, taking this opportunity, I'd be so happy if we could do more singing as a trio and try new challenges!
いいですか？ハモりを重ねていきましょう！
Is it okay? Let's stack up those harmonies!
え、いいの？！ユニット名とか欲しいな！
Wait, really?! I'd love a unit name!
確かに！え、何だろう？世界目指せるくらいの...
Right! I wonder what? Something grand enough to aim for the world...
世界！？
The world?!
世界、世界のコンサートしようよ！
Yes, let's do a world concert tour!
やりたいやりたい！世界に届く！
We want to! Reaching the world!
何かをしたいということで、3人でライブとか、アコースティックとか、オーケストラライブとか！
With that in mind, maybe a live show, acoustic set, or even an orchestral live concert!
よくないですか？そんなこともしてみたい！
Doesn't that sound great? I'd love to try that!
我らならできるかもしれない！お、願いできる、お願いします！
We might actually be able to pull it off! Our wishes might come true, please make it happen!
あれ？これ、これは一体、何ですか？
Oh? What on earth is this?
もしかして、このライブで、みんなからの、なんかいいパワーで...
Could it be, with all the great power from everyone during this live show...
なんかいいパワー来てる！儀式じゃん、それ！
Some good power is coming! That's like a ritual!
何だよそのパワー！こちらがなんと、完成しました！
What is that power anyway?! This has finally been completed!
何それ何それ！
What is that, what is that?!
実は、このあと、アキロゼの新曲が...
Actually, after this, AkiRose's new song...
出ます！わー！出た！
will be released!
こちら、今回のライブのテーマというか、壮大なテーマがあるんですけれども、そちらの詰まったような楽曲になっています。
This song encapsulates the grand theme of this live show.
そして、ライブ終わりの日付が変わるときにリリースしますので、ぜひ聴いてください！聴く！絶対に聴く！行くぞー！
And it will be released as the date changes after the live, so please be sure to listen to it!
じゃあ次の曲に行きますか？
Well, shall we move on to the next song?
次の曲、はい、新曲のお披露目、しちゃいます！
For the next song, yes, I'll be performing my new song for the first time!
なんだってー！もう新曲お披露目、え、今からってこと？
What?! Revealing the new song... wait, right now?!
今から頑張ります！最後まで見逃せないですね！楽しみだ！
I'll do my best starting now! You can't miss it until the very end!
頑張ってね！バイバイ！頑張りコポリー！頑張るよー！
Good luck! Bye-bye! Do your best! I will!
モノポリー
Monopoly
魅惑の言葉通り
Just as the charming words say,
裏面に忍ばせた
hidden on the reverse side...
1mgのスパイス
is a 1mg spice.
たちまち華麗な
Instantly, with elegant...
指先で彩る
...fingertips, I color...
本日のダイス
...today's dice.
当たり見て妥協してちゃ
If you settle just by looking at the wins,
生き残れないでしょう
you won't survive, will you?
率直に言って
To be frank,
その全てが欲しい
I want all of it.
一人勝ちにオールイン
All-in for a solo victory.
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃない Duet
No matter what happens, isn't it fine?
際限なんてないじゃない
There are no limits, are there?
翻弄して 翻弄されて ゾクゾク
Toying with, being toyed with, getting thrills.
喰らっちゃっても本望でしょ
Even if I get taken down, it's what I want, right?
最低だって滾るでしょ
Even at the worst, it's thrilling, right?
見透かして 見透かされて 故に 終わりは無い
Seeing through, being seen through, therefore there is no end.
高鳴るこの全てノンフィクション
All of this throbbing is non-fiction.
嗜むはずでも
Even if I only meant to enjoy a little,
たまには飲みすぎて
sometimes I drink too much,
1回休み
and lose a turn.
周りもざわつく
Making those around me stir,
思わぬうたた寝で
due to an unexpected nap,
2回休み
lose two turns.
切れる手札と勘だけじゃ
With just playable cards and intuition alone,
手に入らないもの
some things are unobtainable.
速攻で行って
Going with a swift attack,
見逃されるならいい
it's fine if it's overlooked.
命懸けで楽しむわ
I'll enjoy this with my life on the line.
天と地は案外近い
Heaven and earth are surprisingly close.
「この通り」
Just as you see,
命懸け
putting my life on the line.
されどモノポリー_text
Yet, it's Monopoly.
されどおじゃり
And so, we feast,
秘める想い
my hidden feelings...
今宵私は強い
tonight, I am strong!
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃない
No matter what happens, isn't it fine?
際限なんてないじゃない
There are no limits, are there?
翻弄して 翻弄されて ゾクゾク
Toying with, being toyed with, getting thrills.
喰らっちゃっても本望でしょ
Even if I get taken down, it's what I want, right?
最低だって滾るでしょ
Even at the worst, it's thrilling, right?
見透かして 見透かされて 故に 終わりは無い
Seeing through, being seen through, therefore there is no end.
高鳴るこの全てノンフィクション
All of this throbbing is non-fiction.
落ちても昇ってもノンフィクション
Whether falling or rising, it's non-fiction.
葛飾ラプソディー
Katsushika Rhapsody
中川に浮かぶ 夕陽をめがけて
Aiming at the setting sun floating on the Nakagawa River,
小石を蹴ったら 靴まで飛んで
when I kicked a pebble, even my shoe flew off.
ジョギングしていた 大工の頭領に
The master carpenter who was jogging
ガキのまんまだと 笑われたのさ
laughed at me, saying I'm still a kid.
どこかに元気を 落っことしても
Even if I drop my energy somewhere,
葛飾亀有 アクビをひとつ
in Katsushika Kameari, I let out a yawn.
変わらない町並みが 妙にやさしいよ保存用
The unchanging townscape is strangely kind.
中央広場で 子供の手を引く
Pulling a child's hand in the central square,
太ったあの娘は 初恋の彼女
that plump girl was my first love.
ゴンパチ池で 渡したラブレター保存用
The love letter I gave her at Gonpachi Pond,
今も持ってると からかわれたよ
she teased me, saying she still has it.
何にもいいこと なかったけど
Nothing good really happened, but
葛飾水元 流れる雲と
with the drifting clouds over Katsushika Mizumoto,
ラプソディー口ずさみ 少し歩こうか
humming a rhapsody, shall we walk a little?
カラスが鳴くから もう日が暮れるね
The crows are cawing, so the sun is already setting, isn't it?
焼鳥ほうばり ビール飲もうか
Let's stuff our cheeks with yakitori and drink beer.
トンガリ帽子の 取水塔から
From the pointed-hat intake tower,
帝釈天へと 夕陽が落ちる
the sunset falls toward Taishakuten.
嫌よ 嫌よも こうして終わるんだね
Even the "no, no" ends like this, doesn't it?
確信犯の 待ち合わせだって
It was a rendezvous of deliberate offenders.
白状して 気がついた
Once confessed, I realized...
バカな本音だったら
...if it was just a foolish truth.
どこかに消えて切符を落としても
Even if the ticket disappears somewhere and I drop it,
確信犯の目配りあくびを一つ
The deliberate offender glances and yawns once.
代わり映えない街並みが
The unchanging cityscape...
妙に優しいよ
...is strangely kind.
アキロゼ生誕祭2026をご覧の皆さん、いかがでしたでしょうか？
Everyone watching Akirose Birthday Celebration 2026, how was it?
さて、ここからは、大事なお知らせがあるので、最後までしっかり聞いていってね！
Now, I have some important announcements, so please listen carefully until the end!
まずは、お知らせ1つ目！アキロゼ生誕祭2026誕生日グッズ、発売です！
First up is the first announcement! Akirose Birthday Celebration 2026 birthday merch is now on sale!
今回は、ライブの世界観をぎゅっと楽しんでもらえるグッズを、頑張って制作いたしました。
This time, we worked hard to create merch that allows you to fully enjoy the worldview of the live show.
なので、今回のライブが良かったなーって思った方は、ぜひ応援で購入していただくのもすごく嬉しいです！
So, if you thought today's live show was great, I'd be super happy if you purchased them to support me!
それでは、まず1つ目のグッズ！Life is GAME ラバーマット！
Now, the first item! The "Life is GAME" rubber mat!
今回のイラストはラム先生に描き下ろしていただきました。素敵なイラストありがとうございます！
The illustration for this was drawn by Lam-sensei. Thank you so much for the wonderful illustration!
今回のライブの世界観をイメージしたイラストになっています。めちゃくちゃセクシーで、色っぽいけどかっこいいような、アキロゼになっています。
It is inspired by the worldview of this live concert. It features Akirose looking super sexy, seductive, yet also cool.
ラバーマットで思う存分楽しんでください。
Please enjoy it to your heart's content with this rubber mat!
ちなみに、サイズはカードゲームにぴったり。この意味、わかるよね？
By the way, the size is perfect for card games. You know what that means, right?
2つ目のグッズが、運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルスタンドセット！
The second item is the "Five Cards of Destiny Tarot-style Acrylic Stand Set"!
アキロゼが、あなたのことを占って、背中を押してあげます。
Akirose will read your fortune and give you a little push.
1日の始まりや、何か運命を託したい、みたいな、そんな時に使って楽しむ。
You can use it and enjoy it at the start of your day, or when you want to leave something up to fate.
そして、5枚バーンって飾っておけるので、見ても楽しめるようになっております。
And since you can display all five cards lined up, it is also visually appealing.
占い方法は、この後紹介するアキロゼのASMRボイスと連動しております。
The fortune-telling method is linked with Akirose's ASMR voice, which I will introduce later.
飾っても楽しい、使っても楽しい、そのような連動グッズになっているので、ぜひゲットしてください。
It is a linked item that is fun to display and fun to use, so please get yours!
続いてのグッズは、アキロゼのトランプ！作っちゃいました！
The next item is "Akirose's Playing Cards"! I went ahead and made them!
こちら、実際に遊んでいただけるトランプなので、たくさん予備も買った方がいいんじゃないかなーと思います。
Since these are actual playing cards you can play with, I think you might want to buy multiple spares!
ぜひトランプでもアキロゼをたくさん楽しんで、アピールしてくださいね。
Please enjoy seeing lots of Akirose even with the playing cards and show them off!
続いては、こちら！アキロゼのカードケース！
Next up is this! The "Akirose Card Case"!
これはもちろん、トランプなど、小物入れても大丈夫です。
Of course, you can also use this for the playing cards or other small items.
ぜひおうちや、持ち歩きに使ってね。
Please use it at home or carry it around with you.
そして、ボイスの紹介です！
And now, here is the introduction of the voices!
今回も、ASMRボイスを特別に発売！
We are releasing special ASMR voices this time too!
アキとロゼが、それぞれ左右からあなたに囁く、誘惑しちゃうかも。
Aki and Rose will whisper to you from left and right, and they might tempt you...
台本も頑張って書いたので、ぜひぜひたっぷり楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I worked hard on the script, so I'd be extremely happy if you enjoyed it to the fullest.
こちらボイスは、Life is GAME ～アキとロゼの盤上～、こちらをメインとし、ASMRショートボイスとして、先ほどの運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルカードと連動した、ショートボイスが入っております。
The main track is "Life is GAME ~Aki and Rose's Board~", and we have included ASMR short voices that link with the "Five Cards of Destiny Tarot-style Acrylic Cards" I showed earlier.
ショートボイスの、シャッフル・ランダム再生をして、選ばれたボイスが、あなたの運命の1枚になります。ぜひ色々楽しんでね！
If you shuffle and play the short voices on random, the voice that plays will represent your destiny card. Please enjoy it in various ways!
これらのグッズ、すべてが詰まった、フルセット購入には、なんと特典もついております。
For those who purchase the Full Set containing all of these items, there's actually a special bonus included!
今回の、キービジュアルのイラストを使った、チケット風カードになっております。
It is a ticket-style card featuring the key visual illustration of this celebration.
あなたは、このゲームに参加する？参加しない？
Will you participate in this game? Or will you not?
こちらも、ライブの世界観を高めるアイテムになっているので、ぜひゲットしてください。
This is also an item that enhances the worldview of the live concert, so make sure to get it.
そして、数量限定、あります！直筆サインと、箔押し複製メッセージが、入ったものになっております。頑張って書きます！
And we also have a limited-quantity edition! It features a hand-signed signature and a hot-stamped replica message. I'll do my best writing them!
そして、数量限定が終わり次第、箔押しでの複製サインと、メッセージが入ったチケット風カードになります。
Once the limited-quantity edition sells out, it will change to a ticket-style card with a hot-stamped replica signature and message.
ぜひフルセット購入特典、ゲットしてね！
Make sure to get the Full Set purchase bonus!
大事な発売時間は、この後、21時30分！21時30分にショップオープンです！
The important release time is right after this, at 21:30! The shop opens at 21:30!
ぜひ登録など、準備して、備えておいてね！
Please get ready, make sure you're registered, and be prepared!
続きまして、お知らせ2つ目！
Next up, the second announcement!
この後、21時45分から、メンバー限定のアフターライブを行います！
After this, starting from 21:45, we will hold a member-only after-show live!
ライブ本編とはまた違う楽曲を、披露する予定なので、ぜひお楽しみに！
We plan to perform songs different from the main concert, so please look forward to it!
今日メンバーになった方も、ぜひぜひ見てね！
Even if you joined today, please come and watch!
ちなみに、過去のライブの、メンバー限定アフ...
By the way, the member-only after-shows of past lives...
...ライブも見れちゃうと思うので、
...I think you'll also be able to watch the live,
ぜひそのあたりも見てみてね！
so please check that out as well!
ちなみに、今回のサムネイルイラストは
By the way, the thumbnail illustration this time
メンバー限定で壁紙としてプレゼント予定です！
will be given as a wallpaper present to members!
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
そして！お知らせ3つ目！
And! The third announcement!
本日の生誕祭ライブの後も、
After today's birthday celebration live,
お楽しみはまだまだ続きます！
the fun is not over yet!
なんと、ホロアースにて特別企画
We will be having a special event in Holoearth,
アキ・ローゼンタール生誕祭アンコール
"Aki Rosenthal Birthday Celebration Encore
イン・ホロアースを開催します！
in Holoearth" will be held!
今回初披露した新曲「モノポリー」を
I will perform my new song "Monopoly",
ホロアースで歌っちゃいます！
revealed for the first time today, in Holoearth!
いろんな角度からアキロゼのパフォーマンスや
Please take a close look at Akirose's performance
演出をじっくりと見てみてくださいね。
and staging from various angles!
さらに、ホロアースだけのお楽しみMCパートもたっぷりあるので、
Additionally, there'll be plenty of fun MC parts exclusive to Holoearth,
ぜひぜひ会いに来てください！
so please, please come see me!
開催日は3月13日、3月13日です！
The event will be held on March 13th, March 13th!
詳細はホロアース公式Xをチェックしてね！
Check Holoearth's official X for details!
そして、最後のお知らせが...
And the final announcement is...
新曲「モノポリー」！
My new song, "Monopoly"!
本日、日付が変わる頃にリリースされますので、
It will be released today as the date changes,
各音楽配信サービスからぜひ購入してね！
so please purchase it from various music distribution services!
たくさん聴いてね！
Listen to it a lot!
振り付けも歌もとってもキャッチーなので、
Both the choreography and the song are very catchy,
覚えてみんなで楽しんでもらえる、
so I hope people learn them, enjoy them together,
愛されるような楽曲になってくれたら嬉しいなって思っています。
and that it becomes a well-loved song.
また、後日ライブ配信で
Also, in a future live stream,
新曲「モノポリー」や今回のライブの後日談を語ったり、
I want to share stories about "Monopoly" and this live,
一緒に見たりなどしたいなと思っているので、
or watch it together with you,
ぜひチャンネル登録、高評価ポチ、通知もオン！
so please subscribe, hit that like button, and turn on notifications!
してないよって人は今ポチッとしてね！
If you haven't yet, click them now!
絶対絶対、また会いに来てね！
Be sure to come see me again!
それでは、
Now then,
運命は時に残酷。
fate is sometimes cruel.
あなたが選びたくて選んだものではないかもしれない。
It might not be something you chose because you wanted to.
だけど、いつでもあなたの人生はあなたのもの。
But your life is always yours.
人生は一度きり。
You only live once.
やり直しのきかないこのゲーム。
In this game with no do-overs...
あなたはどう楽しむ？
how will you enjoy it?